Pablo Martín Calvo

Data Engineer

CONTACT INFORMATION

E-mail: pablomc87@gmail.com

Address: 3 rue Lavoisier, 93500 Pantin (France)

Phone: +33652217711

Link to portfolio: https://pablomc87.github.io/

SUMMARY

Data Engineer with solid experience in developing and optimizing data pipelines, database management, and Python programming, I seek to bring my skills to a dynamic team. Diplomatic, adaptable, and capable of working under pressure thanks to my experience as an elite handball referee

EXPERIENCE

namR

Sep 2023 - Sep 2024

Data Engineer

- Database management: Model management, maintenance, SQL query optimization, data security
- · Creation and maintenance of ETL: Audit, maintenance, and optimization of Python code
- · Task automation: reporting, monitoring, service migration

Tech stack: Python / PostgreSQL / GCP / Airflow / Kubernetes / Terraform / Dataiku / GitLab CI/CD / API

SamuSocial de Paris

Sep 2022 - Jul 2023

Data Analyst

- Development of a web application to automate activity tracking and reporting: 54,000 people housed per day, 400M annual budget, 11 different partners
- · Creation of annual, monthly, weekly reports and presentation to teams

Tech stack: Python / PostgreSQL / SQL / Dash / Plotly / Excel / Cron jobs / PPT

Salto

May 2022 - Jul 2022

Data Analyst

- Enrichment of consumption data on BigQuery: API queries and table updates
- Production deployment with Cloud Functions and Scheduler
- · Data analysis and visualization

Tech stack: Python / SQL / GCP / BigQuery / Dash / Plotly / Google Data Studio

Student projects

Mar 2022 - May 2022

Data Analyst

- Film recommendation system for a fictional client (6 weeks)
- Web application with integrated Machine Learning model (Nearest Neighbors)
- · Dynamic dashboard for a fictional client (3 weeks)

Tech stack: Python / SQL / GCP / Dash / Plotly / Tableau / Machine Learning

EDUCATION

Sep 2023 - Sep 2024

Data Engineer

Wild Code School

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Data Analyst
Wild Code School

Sep 2017 - Oct 2018

Master's Degree in International Cooperation in Education and Training

Paris V Descartes - Sorbonne

LANGUAGES

SKILLS

English Advanced Python AWS Airflow

French Advanced Git, GitHub, GitLab YAML

Spanish Native

Kubernetes (Notions)

Dataiku Jira

Problem-solving Algorithms Organization

SQL GCP Docker CI/CD Bash / Linux Terraform (notions)

Hadoop, Spark (Notions) React Decision-making

Rigor Leadership